{"data":[{"question":"Two children _____ (play) on the sand and two fishermen _____ (lean) against an upturned boat.","a":"were playing\/was leaning","b":"was playing\/were leaning","c":"were playing\/were leaning","answer":"3","explain":"- Using the past continuous to say that somebody was in the middle of doing something at a certain time in the past","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"11","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"6"},{"question":"From the sounds it was clear that Mary _____ (practise) the piano.","a":"was practiseing","b":"was practising","c":"were practiseing","d":"were practising","answer":"2","explain":"- Using the past continuous to say that somebody was in the middle of doing something at a certain time in the past (Mary was...)","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"11","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"He was a little mad. He always _____ (try) to prove that the earth was flat.","a":"was always trying","b":"were always trying","c":"was always tring","answer":"1","explain":"- Using the past continuous to say that somebody was in the middle of doing something at a certain time in the past","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"11","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"6"},{"question":"It was a fine day and the roads were crowded because a lot of people _____ (rush) to the seaside.","a":"was rushing","b":"were rushing","answer":"2","explain":"- rush -> rushing.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"11","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"},{"question":"When I arrived at the meeting the first speaker had just finished speaking and the audience _____ (clap).","a":"was claping","b":"were claping","c":"was clapping","answer":"3","explain":"- clap -> clapping.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"11","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"6"},{"question":"Tom ate nothing for lunch because he _____ (diet). He said that he _____ (try) to lose 10 kilos.","a":"was dieting\/was trying","b":"were dieting\/was trying","c":"were dieting\/were trying","answer":"1","explain":"- diet -> dieting.\n- try -> trying.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"11","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"6"},{"question":"He usually wears sandals but when I last saw him he _____ (wear) boots.","a":"were wearing","b":"was wearing","answer":"2","explain":"- Using the past continuous to say that somebody was in the middle of doing something at a certain time in the past","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"11","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"},{"question":"While he _____ (learn) to drive he had twenty-five accidents.","a":"was learning","b":"were learning","c":"was learnning","d":"were learnning","answer":"1","explain":"- Using the past continuous to say that somebody was in the middle of doing something at a certain time in the past","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"11","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"The children were frightened because it _____ (get) dark.","a":"were getting","b":"was getting","c":"were geting","d":"was geting","answer":"2","explain":"- get -> getting.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"11","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"He had a bad fall while he _____ (repair) his roof.","a":"were repairing","b":"was repairing","c":"were repaireing","d":"was repaireing","answer":"2","explain":"- Using the past continuous to say that somebody was in the middle of doing something at a certain time in the past","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"11","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"}]}